Wajahat Haider

(+92-330-2472539 I ⊠: wajahathaider98@gmail.com | In linkedin.com/in/wajahat-haider-01207a15a

Summary

Accepting challenges in professional life with an aim to contribute positively towards the achievement of objectives to the best of my capabilities and to develop and improve my professional skills in a growing organization. Developing software is fairly addictive and never make me bored. I have gained 3 years of diversified experience working as a software engineer, can provide effective bridge between business and technical functions and act as a key player in team for goal achievement.

SKILLS

BACK-END DEVELOPMENT | .Net/.Net Core • Entity Framework (EF) Core

• Rest APIs • WCF(SOAP) • Python • Java

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT | Angular • JavaScript • jQuery • Ajax • Typescript • Bootstrap • Materialize • HTML • CSS

MISCELLANEOUS | CQRS • Mediator Pattern using mediatr lib • TDD • RabbitMQ SOFT SKILLS | Team player • Bias for action • Deliver results

EXPERIENCE

HBL (Innovation & Financial Inclusion) | Product Development Engineer | Mar 2022 - Present

- Responsible for analysis and development of the projects features related to Branchless-Banking Agent Network that serve more than 75K Agent nationwide with millions of transactions per day.
- My core duties include designing solutions, preparing functional specification as per business requirement, develop accordingly, perform unit testing and deployment of solution.
- I also mange's technical documentation such as FSD (Functional Specifications Document).
- Working as a vendor resource provided by Winklin.

Projects: Merchant Onboarding (Web App), Digital Credit (Loan Disbursement Services Web & Android App)

Dadatech.ca | Software Developer | Remote Part-Time | Dec 2022 - Present

- Responsible to analysis, design and develop new features of a Canadian bank application
- I also did integration with Bridge systems to maintain all of their tenant transaction records and maintain their chart of account too.

Project: FUSEAPI (eBanking App)

StarSys Solutions | Software Developer | Jul 2020 - Feb 2022

- Responsible to maintain software and develop new features wrt client requirements.
- Design and develop solutions by consume SDK to communicate with multiple attendance devices and create a full options software that manages their attendance and payroll.
- I also developed Visitor Management System and Gym Management System for Starsys clients.

Project: TimePay (Attendance/Payroll Management System)

EDUCATION

PAF KIET - BS Computer Science (BSCS) Dec 2022 | CGPA 3.2/4 Karachi, Pakistan.

HONORS & AWARDS

Scholarships Award | For students having 3.8+ GPA | Oct 2019 | x1

PAF KIET OOP Pro Battle | awarded as the Runner Up of the competition | Oct 2019

ICPC-GIKI Islamabad | got 21st position out of 110 team appeared | Nov 2019

PAF KIET FLAIR'19 Pro Battle | awarded as the Runner Up of the competition | Jun 2020

COURSEWORK

Data Structures and Algorithms
Object Oriented Programing
Design Patterns
Database Management System
Developing Web Apps
Machine Learning